Guide to the John O'Toole Papers, 1954-1990 and undated RL.00983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches, 1969-1990 and undated, 7 boxes
  - Speech I've Successfully Avoided Giving Up to Now, Audit Bureau of Circulations, 1976 Oct. 20 (Box 40)
  - Strategy Development System, 1984 (Box 41)
  - Talking to Persons is Better Than Talking to People, Bank of Marketing Associations, 1971 May 26 (Box 41)
  - Talking to Persons, Not People, Danish Marketing Association, 1975 Mar. 19 (Box 41)
  - Television Bureau of Advertising, 1985 Feb. (Box 41)
  - Television Commercial of Tomorrow
    - AAAA Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box 41)
    - AAAA Western Regional Meeting, 1980 Oct. 18 (Box 41)
    - Financial Advertising and Marketing Association, 1983 Jan. 20 (Box 41)
    - FCB Account Management Conference, 1980 Sept. 17 (Box 41)
  - TV Copy Testing, undated (Box 41)
  - TV Spots, U.S. News & World Report articles, 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - Times Books files, 1984-1990 (Box 41)
  - Trouble with Advertising
    - General files, 1985 (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 41)
    - Revision I, undated (Box 41)
  - Unexpected, Advanced Advertising Program, 1985 Jun. 17 (Box 41)
  - What Fun Is a Recession if You Can't Learn from It?"
    - Los Angeles Sales and Marketing Executives Association, 1975 Dec. 3 (Box 41)
    - Sales Executive Club of New York, 1976 Oct. 22 (Box 41)
  - What I Did on my Summer Vacation, Los Angeles Advertising Club, 1976 Sept. 15 (Box 41)
  - What's Going On In Advertising?, New York Times speech, 1983 Feb.; 1983 Sept. 30 (Box 41)
  - What the Heck is Creativity?, Creative Training Program, 1977 Jul. 1 (Box 41)
  - Whitner Advertising Copy in the Regulatory Age, 1973 (Box 41)
  - Why Would Anyone Write a Book about Advertising?
    - AAAA Eastern Regional Conference, 1982 Jan. 14 (Box 41)
    - Mexican Advertising Agencies Association, 1982 Nov. 4 (Box 41)
    - National Agri-Marketing Association Eastern Chapter Annual Advertising Awards Banquet, 1982 Mar. 18 (Box 41)
  - William Witter, Inc. presentation, 1971 Jun. 29 (Box 41)
  - Worldwide Managers Meeting speech, 1984 Jun. (Box 41)
  - You Is a Singular Pronoun, Broadcast Executives Society, 1971 Mar. 4 (Box 41)
  - Your Lips Are Moving, Tucson Ad Club, 1970 Feb. 24 (Box 41)
  - 80s are Coming!, Bank Marketing Association, 1977 Nov. 2 (Box 41)
- Audiovisual Materials, undated, 1 box
  Includes a reel of advertisements presented at a World Creative Directors' Conference, a reel of advertising spots for Merrill Lynch, and a recording of the song Quick Changes, to which John O'Toole wrote the lyrics.
  - Historical Presentation, World Creative Directors' Conference, Canary Islands. Format: 16mm. Undated (Box 42)
  - Merrill Lynch. Format: 16mm. Undated (Box 42)
  - Quick Changes, song recording. Format: Audiotape. Undated. (Box 42)
    [Music by Bill Walker, lyrics by John O'Toole.]
- Oversize Materials, 1965-1982 and undated, 1 box
  Series includes oversize items removed from previous series. Organized alphabetically.
  - Administrative Files (Box 43)
    - Bipartisan Budget, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Memorabilia, pre-1970, 1965-1968 and undated (Box 43)
    - Memorabilia, 1970-1979 (Box 43)
  - Client Files
    - Sunkist, proofs, undated (Box 43)
  - Correspondence
    - Newspapers of the Future, 1971 (Box 43)
    - O'Toole memoranda, 1974 (Box 43)
    - Public Service, contributions, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Song writing, undated (Box 43)
    - 100 Best Television Commercials, 1981 (Box 43)
  - International Offices
    - Sydney, 1982 (Box 43)
  - Reports
    - National Advertising Review Board Product Advertising and Consumer Safety Report, 1974 (Box 43)
    - Political Advertising, 1971 (Box 43)
      [Includes FCB brochure.]
  - Writings and Speeches
    - Advocacy Advertising, 1974 (Box 43)
    - CLIO Awards Show, 1982 Jun. 11 (Box 43)
    - Mexican Advertising Agency Association, 1982 Nov. 4 (Box 43)